CV for Jon Robinson Levy

Personal data

Name Jon Robinson Levy Born December 13, 1968

Address Vodroffsvej 22A, 3.th, 1900 Frederiksberg C, Denmark

Phone +45 25656690

Email jon.r.levy@gmail.com Family Single; 2 sons (18 &13).

Short Description

Self-educated programmer/developer with 25 years of professional experience, covering times of self-employment/contracting, and times as employee.

Experiences cover a wide spectrum, from old school development on a mainframe, to early client/server systems, to internet based solutions and app development (mobile and PC).

This has provided wide knowledge of languages, techniques, and tools, as well as a lot of experience with databases.

From 2007 development has almost exclusively been for .Net platform in C#, using many of the technologies natural for that platform – Asp.Net, UWP, Azure to mention a few.

Has worked a good deal with the Twitter API, both with sites, apps and background tasks using it.

For the last couple of years development have primarily been Apps, in UWP, and Xamarin. Is certified Xamarin developer.

Describes himself as analytical, cooperative, quality conscious, and independent. And probably somewhat geeky/eccentric.

Does not have much experience (or interest) in project management, but is normally good at grasping and remembering the details of a project, so a typical role is as right hand to a project manager.

Experiences

Programming Languages

- C++ (10 years)
- C# (9 years)
- C (5 years)
- Java (3 years)
- COBOL (5 years)
- XAML (3 years)
- HTML
- JavaScript
- SAS, Visual Basic (VB6), Forth, Clarion, Pascal, Assembler (Z80)

Operating Systems:

- MS-DOS (10 years)
- Windows 3.0-Windows 10 (25 years)
- Unix/Linux (3 years)
- OS (Unisys 2200, 3 years)
- Android

Databases

- MS SQL Server (or SQL Database / Azure) (6 years)
- RDBMS (Unisys, 3 years)
- DB2 (2 years)
- Oracle (2½ years)
- SQLite
- IDBMS
- Various other SQL based

Technologies & concepts

- .NET
- Asp.Net
- UWP
- Xamarin
- XAML
- MVVM
- Client/Server
- Tuxedo
- IIS/ISAPI
- Visual Studio
- DVCS (Git)
- CVCS (TFS, SVN)
- Azure (Wep Apps, Mobile Apps, SQL database)

- MVC
- Web Forms
- Web API/Service
- ASP "classic"
- MFC
- EDI
- XML/WML
- COM/ActiveX

Fields

- Development and maintenance of large administrative systems (5 years)
- Own application development (5 years)
- Contracting (5 years)
- Web/Server applications (11 years)

Samples

Presentation App

JRL Greetings, a small app where I present myself, in the form of a little adventure. More about the app here.

Published

Twewind; a UWP-app for recording events on Twitter: http://twewind.com/
Dice Champ: A Xamarin (D&D dice rolling) app, in Google Play and Windows Store.

Code

I've got a couple of small utility Class Libraries (C#) on BitBucket, which might give a general impression on coding style: https://bitbucket.org/JonRLevy/jrlutilities/ (a general utility library) and https://bitbucket.org/JonRLevy/mvvmbase (a MVVM base library).

Employments

Self-employed

(2012-)

Have primarily been working on the development of a Twitter relationship monitoring system, as well as smaller apps for Windows and Windows Phone/Mobile, also with a focus on Twitter; lately mostly cross platform development in Xamarin. (.Net / C# / Asp.Net / XAML / UWP / Xamarin / Web Services, APIs / Azure)

Illness

(2010-2012)

During my work for KPLL I was hit by a major depression, which eventually led to my quitting the job – a job I was rather happy with, but I didn't feel I could perform to my own expectations. Since then my mother was hit by cancer, and I had to take care of her until her death in 2012.

KPLL

(2008-2010)

Development of web based lab result reporting system (for General Practitioners), as well as web services connected to sundhed.dk. Development of internal monitoring and reporting systems, and systems integration in a rather heterogeneous environment.

Dansk Aktionærforening (2007-2007)

Worked for 4 months on converting an ASP-site to Asp.Net/C# (Web Forms), and development of a portfolio management system (also Asp.Net/C#).

Self-employed (2002-2007)

After Handshake Technologies I continued development for the owner of the technology, the former CEO. Also did a good deal of customer assignments (html/css).

Handshake Technologies A/S (2001-2002)

After Handshake Systems went bankrupt, the core development continued in Handshake Technologies.

Handshake Systems ApS (2000-2001)

Development of the CMS Helium (C++ and Java for ISAPI / Windows 2000). Also development of a site administration tool (the server part) for Mobilix (Orange).

Self-employed (1994-2000)

Quit DSB with the idea of creating a graphical MUD, but soon ran out of money. Then did contracting for DSB (COBOL / Mainframe), and later Rigshospitalet (Copenhagen University Hospital), working on monitoring and reporting programs (mainly in SAS and SQL).

DSB EDB-tjenesten (1990-1994)

Most of the time I worked in COBOL with the GTX-system (a freight administration system). Participated in major project – an experiment in integrating the mainframe with Unix and PCs: client/server, very new concept for DSB at the time... The last part of my employment I worked in the S-Tog department, on a traffic monitoring system (C/Unix).

Self-employed (1989-1990)

Developed Structure Chart, a design tool, which I sold to (among others) DSB. Later did contracting for DSB, before they hired me.

Systemata, contracting for ICL (1988-1988)

Worked with the 4GL QuickBuild on top of COBOL and ICL's IDBMS on a major administrative system.

Languages

Danish (native) and English (fluent).

Education

I am self-educated, with no formal degrees; originally started programming when I was approximately 11/12, in 1981 – I was taught Fortran on a Sperry Univac by my father. Dropped out of high school in first year.

Certifications, badges, courses

I am certified Xamarin Mobile Developer and Xamarin Mobile Professional from Xamarin

University, from which I have also obtained an Azure Mobile Developer Badge:



I've got badges for ASP.NET Core 2.0, DevOps for Developers, and MEAN Stack Development from Microsoft Virtual Academy:



In addition, I've been taking courses since the early Nineties. Most are hardly relevant today, the latest were in database administration for Oracle and SQL Server in 2008.

Interests

Books, Dungeons & Dragons, Writing, Photography, TV Series, Twitter